I came over to Shirli's house in the middle of the night with a ukulele.
我半夜带着尤克里里去Shirli家
He was playing this beautiful chord change
他弹奏着美妙的和弦
and I was like "what's that?".
而我很吃惊地问道 这是什么
I don't remember exactly what she said
我不记得她具体说了什么
but it was like "Is that a real instrument?".
大概是像 这是真正的乐器吗 一类的问题
And I was like "Yeah, it's a real trend now. A lot of people run it off as a toy".
然后我就这样回答 没错 尤克里里最近很风靡 许多人把它当玩具玩
I had witnessed similarly except night at the bar I was working at.
这和我在酒吧的工作完全不同
So I pulled the lyrics out
所以我把歌词写了出来
and I started singing over whatever he was playing.
然后根据Austin弹奏的音乐歌唱
And we wrote Game Called Life in about five minutes.
我们差不多五分钟内就写好了Game Called Life这首歌
注:
the Big C是2010年8月16日首播的美剧，Leftover Cuties第一部专辑Game Called Life EP发布于2009年
(EP指extended-playing record，歌曲数量介于单曲single和专辑album之间，一般是正式专辑发布前的试水作)
Having Game Called Life as a theme song for the Big C.
Game Called Life被选作电视剧the Big C的主题曲
It's been incredible.
确实难以想象
Overwhelming, I mean.
这真是令人不知所措
I wrote that song kind of wondering what the hell am I doing with my life.
我创作这首歌曲的动机是感叹我这糟蹋的人生
To realize that somebody that has been diagnosed with cancer can relate to it on that level.
这首歌被选中后我才意识到有些患有癌症的人也会为此共鸣
I felt like the song did something greater than I meant for it to do.
我认为这首歌比我预想的起到的意义更大
Then started with Austin and I basically writing songs and recording little demos at my house.
然后我和Austin继续在我家里为试制歌曲谱曲写词
Just with the ukulele, my vocals.
只是尤克里里伴奏 我来演唱
With that couples of noise makers, shakers or kazoo or whatever was lying around the house.
当然还用到了家里的一些乐器 譬如沙铃 卡祖笛之类
We thought there was a certain charm to the way was so raw and so broken down.
我们相信原生和悲伤的风格肯定有不少魅力
注:
Ryan Hewitt is an American music producer, engineer and mixer known for his work with The Lumineers,
Red Hot Chili Peppers, The Avett Brothers, The Dixie Chicks, Third Eye Blind, Jamie Cullum, John Frusciante
and the Turnpike Troubadours.
以上截自维基百科，大概就是一个很有名的音乐制作人
You know when time had passed we sought out Ryan Hewitt.
过段时间后 我们找到了Ryan Hewitt
And he was like "All these are great songs".
他说 这些都是很好的歌曲
"But if you guys want to sell records you're gonna need to get some drums."
但是你们想发行唱片的话还需要一点鼓声
A light came on Shirli(?) and I said like "I know the drummer that's perfect for this".
我突然想起确实有一个鼓手适合这个位置
It was Stuart.
他就是Stuart
One of the most musical drummers I've ever met.
我见过的最优音乐天赋的鼓手之一
We went over to his house and...
我们去了他家
Look Ok. Play something for me.
他说 看着不错 你们给我来一段
She played the song and music.
Shirli弹唱了一会
It's some kind of sad that he didn't say much.
Stuart话说得很少 似乎不是很高兴
And he said, "Hold on."
之后他说 等等
He ran his house, started grabbing some stuff.
他跑回家里 找着些东西
Back in stuck around like throwing pots and pans down or something.
似乎是卡住了 翻找了好多东西
When I heard ukulele being played I thought what can I played not to overpower that.
听了尤克里里以后 我感觉我使用的乐器不应该压制住它的声音
Drums could crush a ukulele pretty quickly
而鼓声很容易盖过尤克里里的声音
but I found some old drums that have calfskin heads on them.
不过我找到了一些用牛皮做的鼓
They're not plastic they have a warmer sound.
因为不是用塑料做的 所以声音温润一些
For surely to flow to vocal over top of.
当然也不会盖过人声
It worked.
这主意起作用了
At that point Stuart have heard our songs maybe a couple of times.
Stuart已经听我们的歌好几次了
So he basically was coming up with ideas and parts on the spot
所以他基本上很快知道怎么做了
when we were at the studio.
当我们在工作室的时候
From there branched out to Ryan Feves.
之后我们找到了Ryan Feves
One day Austin call me,
有天Austin打电话给我说
"hey, do you want to play bass in my ukulele band?"
嘿 你想在我们乐队弹奏低音提琴吗
And the way it sounded had the picture in my head.
他说这话的时候 我就在想
A bunch of people with the abilities.
这肯定是一群有才能的人
We had real event a little bit.
我们正式演出过几次
He's almost too good.
他实在太棒了
Of a musician, has too good of chops to play in the Leftover Cuties.
作为一个音乐家 在Leftover Cuties里他擅长的乐器太多了
The most recent addition is Mike Bolgar.
最近加入的成员是Mike Bolgar
He's one of those guys that you can call up for anything any situation
他是那种任何情况下都随叫随到的人
and he'll come and play exactly what you want to hear.
并且能弹奏出任何你想听到的音乐
He was basically the missing piece, you know.
他差不多就是我们乐队欠缺的那部分
Once he got into the band, I think we all really felt like we finally have a full sound.
当他加入乐队的时候 我觉得我们乐队终于完整了
注:
这个视频在2011年5月25日发布的，指的专辑应该是这个时间附近发布的Places To Go，而EP指的是Game Called Life EP
The album, compared to the EP,
现在这个专辑 相比于EP
it's just, it's grown.
已经发展了很多
Leftover Cuties was a new place for all of us.
Leftover Cuties是我们所有人的新家
It's a place where we could be free and express ourselves
我们在这可以自由地表现自己
and be playful and be light-hearted
可以无忧无虑地开玩笑
and also deep and emotional.
也可以充满感情地深入表达
There's so many different elements to it and in so many places that it takes you.
这个专辑每处都有不同的元素能打动你
And it's just the beginning, you know.
而这仅仅是一个开始
It's the first album.
这是我们的第一个专辑
So, it's gonna be quite a ride.
所以这将是一段不错的旅途